<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Zhanliang Liu</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Zhanliang Liu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>pullword: Unsupervised Word Discovery</title>
      <link>/project/pullword/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pullword/</guid>
      <description>Introduction With the growing availability of digitized text data, there is a great need for effective computational tools to automatically extract kownledge from texts.
The Chinese language differs most significantly from alphabet-based languages in not specifying word boundaries, most existing Chinese text-mining methods require a prespecified vocabulary and/or a large relevant training corpus, which may not be available in some applications.
Pullword is developed for word discovering from small/large volumes of unstructured Chinese texts, and propose ways to order discovered words and conduct higher-level context analyses and it is particularly useful for mining online and domain-specific texts where the underlying vocabulary is unknown or the texts of interest differ significantly from available training corpora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMR: functional meaning representation</title>
      <link>/project/fmr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/fmr/</guid>
      <description>Element types in FMR  Constants: Refer to specific objects in the world. A constant can be a number, a lexical string, or an entity. Classes: Semantic category of entities. For example: location.city, math.number  Sub-class: math.number ⊆ math.expression Template classes: classes with one or more parameters, for example: t.list&amp;lt;c, m, n&amp;gt;, where c is a class, m and n are integers.  Functions: The major way to form larger language units from smaller ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gocc: Golang version OpenCC 繁簡轉換</title>
      <link>/project/gocc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/gocc/</guid>
      <description>Introduction 介紹 gocc is a golang port of OpenCC(Open Chinese Convert 開放中文轉換) which is a project for conversion between Traditional and Simplified Chinese developed by BYVoid.
gocc stands for &amp;ldquo;Golang version OpenCC&amp;rdquo;, it is a total rewrite version of OpenCC by Go. It just borrows the dict files and config files of OpenCC, so it may not produce the same output with the original OpenCC.
Installation 安裝 1, golang package go get github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ling: A Natural Language Processing toolkit in Golang</title>
      <link>/project/ling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ling/</guid>
      <description>other NLP tools  Stanford CoreNLP Java spaCy Python lingo Golang  Multilingual text toknization  Unicode Standard Annex #29 blevesearch segment  Text normalization  Text normalization in Go  Lemmatization  词干提取（stemming）和词形还原（lemmatization）
  Stemming and lemmatization Lemmatization ListsDatasets by MBM  The UniMorph Project 中文繁简转换  gocc Golang version OpenCC OpenCC Chinese-Character Jian&amp;lt;=&amp;gt;Fan converting library in Go Traditional and Simplified Chinese Conversion in Go Han unification   Tagging  Regex tagger  commonregex, a collection of common regular expressions for Go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goobot: A general multilingual web article extractor</title>
      <link>/project/goobot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/goobot/</guid>
      <description> 实现新闻网页标题、时间、正文、图片和视频的抽取 对全球多语种站点通用，高效稳定 代码开源：https://github.com/crawlerclub/ce 演示地址：http://goobot.org/  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge extraction from web pages</title>
      <link>/project/knowledge-extraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/knowledge-extraction/</guid>
      <description> 数据源  某搜索引擎网页库 Common Crawl Corpus  根据号码在网页中出现的位置采用相应的方法  meta标签、microdata：结构化数据抽取 网页头尾：基于规则的抽取系统 网页正文：  人工总结号码信息特征（HTML标签结构特征，文本特征等） 机器学习进行信息抽取和分类    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Crawling at Scale</title>
      <link>/project/web-crawling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/web-crawling/</guid>
      <description>Web crawling is at the core of many data businesses. Whether you call it web crawling, web or screen scraping, or mining the web, it involves going to sites or json apis on the web, grabbing pages, and parsing them to pull out links, images, text, prices, titles, email addresses, and numerous other page attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>