<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NLU on Zhanliang Liu</title>
    <link>/tags/nlu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NLU on Zhanliang Liu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/nlu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Language Model Is All You Need — Explores NLU as MRC QA</title>
      <link>/post/qanlu-language-model-is-all-you-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/qanlu-language-model-is-all-you-need/</guid>
      <description>New research from Amazon Alexa AI posits that current natural language understanding (NLU) approaches are far from how humans understand language, and asks whether all NLU problems could be efficiently and effectively mapped to question-answering (QA) problems using transfer learning.
Transfer learning is an ML approach for applying knowledge learned from a source domain to a target domain. It has produced promising results in natural language processing (NLP), particularly when transferring learning from high data domains to low data domains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>⛵ Learning Meaning in Natural Language Processing — The Semantics Mega-Thread</title>
      <link>/post/semantic-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/semantic-meaning/</guid>
      <description>I found a very worthwhile article while surfing medium.com days ago. The article is a summary of a twitter thread which talked about meaning, semantics, language models, learning Thai and Java, entailment, co-reference — all in one fascinating thread. The original article is here.
Following is a copy of the original article:
Last week a tweet by Jacob Andreas triggered a huge discussion on Twitter that many people have called the meaning/semantics mega-thread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pullword: Unsupervised Word Discovery</title>
      <link>/project/pullword/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pullword/</guid>
      <description>Introduction With the growing availability of digitized text data, there is a great need for effective computational tools to automatically extract kownledge from texts.
The Chinese language differs most significantly from alphabet-based languages in not specifying word boundaries, most existing Chinese text-mining methods require a prespecified vocabulary and/or a large relevant training corpus, which may not be available in some applications.
Pullword is developed for word discovering from small/large volumes of unstructured Chinese texts, and propose ways to order discovered words and conduct higher-level context analyses and it is particularly useful for mining online and domain-specific texts where the underlying vocabulary is unknown or the texts of interest differ significantly from available training corpora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMR: functional meaning representation</title>
      <link>/project/fmr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/fmr/</guid>
      <description>Element types in FMR  Constants: Refer to specific objects in the world. A constant can be a number, a lexical string, or an entity. Classes: Semantic category of entities. For example: location.city, math.number  Sub-class: math.number ⊆ math.expression Template classes: classes with one or more parameters, for example: t.list&amp;lt;c, m, n&amp;gt;, where c is a class, m and n are integers.  Functions: The major way to form larger language units from smaller ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ling: A Natural Language Processing toolkit in Golang</title>
      <link>/project/ling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ling/</guid>
      <description>other NLP tools  Stanford CoreNLP Java spaCy Python lingo Golang  Multilingual text toknization  Unicode Standard Annex #29 blevesearch segment  Text normalization  Text normalization in Go  Lemmatization  词干提取（stemming）和词形还原（lemmatization）
  Stemming and lemmatization Lemmatization ListsDatasets by MBM  The UniMorph Project 中文繁简转换  gocc Golang version OpenCC OpenCC Chinese-Character Jian&amp;lt;=&amp;gt;Fan converting library in Go Traditional and Simplified Chinese Conversion in Go Han unification   Tagging  Regex tagger  commonregex, a collection of common regular expressions for Go.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>