<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithm on Zhanliang Liu</title>
    <link>/tags/algorithm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algorithm on Zhanliang Liu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/algorithm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Filtered-Space Saving Top-K</title>
      <link>/post/topk-in-stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/topk-in-stream/</guid>
      <description>Before diving into Filtered-Space Saving algorithm, let us talk about the Space-Saving algorithm first, it was proposed by Metwally et al. in [1]. Space-Saving underlying idea is to monitor only a pre-defined number of m elements and their associated counters. Counters on each element are updated to reflect the maximum possible number of times an element has been observed and the error that might be involved in that estimate. If an element that is already being monitored occurs again, the counter for the frequency estimate is incremented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weighted Random: algorithms for sampling from discrete probability distributions</title>
      <link>/post/weighted-random/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/weighted-random/</guid>
      <description>Introduction First of all what is weighted random? Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a list of items and you want to pick one of them randomly. Doing this seems easy as all that&amp;rsquo;s required is to write a litte function that generates a random index referring to the one of the items in the list. But sometimes plain randomness is not enough, we want random results that are biased or based on some probability.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>